Thomas Szasz Papers
Thomas Szasz Papers
- Recordings
  - Videorecordings
    - "OCD" 20/20; "John Henckley, Sr." Today, 03/19/1987; 04/16/1987; szasz_t_051; VHS (Box 78)
    - PAL Copy Dr. T. Szasz's Seminar, 11/02/1989; szasz_t_014; VHS (Box 76)
    - People Say I'm Crazy, 1989; szasz_t_218; VHS; running time 56:00 (Box 87)
    - Philip Morris Award Ceremony, 7/22/1987; szasz_t_214; VHS; running time 27:00 (Box 87)
    - Preliminary Edited Version: Dr. Thomas Szasz (copy 6), 4/29/1993; szasz_t_223; VHS; running time 23:00 (Box 88)
    - Programa El Mirador: Entrevista Dr. Thomas Szasz, szasz_t_235; VHS; running time 120:00 (Box 88)
    - Psyc. 205 Telecourse: Interview Dr. Thomas Szasz.; Mental Illness & Suicide; Drugs & Schizophrenia, szasz_t_037; VHS (Box 77)
    - "Reconsider" Program #17, 07/12/1995; szasz_t_079; VHS; running time 00:29:20 (Box 78)
    - "Reconsider" Program #18, 07/12/1995; szasz_t_080; VHS; running time 00:29:13 (Box 78)
    - Ron Schuver Interview, 8/1988; szasz_t_215; VHS; running time 120:00 (Box 87)
    - Sally Jesse Raphael Postpartum Psychosis; Mike Tyson 20/20, 06/09/1988; 09/30/1988; szasz_t_047; VHS (Box 78)
    - "Schizophrenia" Bettelheim, Laing, Szasz, Whitaker, szasz_t_043; VHS (Box 77)
    - Sixty Minutes/ Schizophrenia; Nightline/ War on Drugs; Firing Line/ A. Dershowitz, 7/27/1986; 8/7/1986; 8/9/1986; szasz_t_213; VHS; running time 120:00 (Box 87)
    - Speaking Out Therapeutic State, szasz_t_045; VHS (Box 77)
    - Szasz Copy #2, 09/25/1999; szasz_t_026; VHS (Box 76)
    - T. Szasz "Meaning of Mind and it's Implications for Psychiatry" ECU Greenville, NC, 09/11/1997; szasz_t_052; VHS (Box 78)
    - T. Szasz "The Film", 1989; szasz_t_120; VHS (Box 82)
    - T. Szasz Reception ECU Greenville, 09/11/1997; szasz_t_053; VHS (Box 78)
    - The Therapeutic State: Past & Future, 11/22/2002; szasz_t_113; lecture by Thomas Szasz, M.D., commentary by Ralph Slovenko, J.D., Ph.D., moderated by Professor Ronald Swartz; additional notes on box; VHS; running time 00:90:00 (Box 80)
    - The Therapeutic State: Past & Future, 11/22/2002; szasz_t_114; lecture by Thomas Szasz, M.D., commentary by Ralph Slovenko, J.D., Ph.D., moderated by Professor Ronald Swartz; additional notes on box; VHS; running time 00:90:00 (Box 80)
    - Ultimate Relationship Program: Enhance Lives Where It Counts Most!, szasz_t_251; Inner Strength Series by Robinson-Madanes (Box 89)
      Unopened set of commercial media and print materials. Contains: 8 full-length DVD films; 8 audio CD programs; 248-page Action book; 100 Daily Discipline Cards; $200 in discount certificates; a free online personal profile.
    - The Verdict of the Foucault Tribunal; a film by Hagai Aviel, szasz_t_022; VHS; running time 01:20:50 (Box 76)
    - Thomas S. Szasz and The Myth of Mental Illness, 1989; szasz_t_119; VHS; running time 00:56:00 (Box 82)
    - Thomas S. Szasz Award Ceremony, Cato Institute, Washington D.C., 02/22/1988; szasz_t_118; VHS (Box 82)
    - Tom Szasz Interview with One "Patient"; U of Ct. H. C., Feb 1988; szasz_t_021; VHS; running time 00:54:16 (Box 76)
    - Tom Szasz Interview, U.C.H.C. Connecticut; Thomas Szasz & "Patient", Feb 1988; szasz_t_034; VHS (Box 77)
    - Uncovering Psychotic Depression: The Hidden Components, szasz_t_229; VHS; running time 10:00 (Box 88)
      Expert Video Program, part 1: Strategies for Diagnosis
    - "Verdict of the Foucault Tribunal" a film by Hagai Aviel, szasz_t_036; VHS (Box 77)
    - Waco, the Big Lie by Linda Thompson, szasz_t_239; commercial product; VHS; running time 32:00 (Box 89)
      Red stamp on the VHS reads: "For more info contact Mr. Peyman at (714) 838-2896)". Additional printed note reads: "Dear Friends and Colleagues: When I viewed this tape I found it puzzling and even shocking. I've purchased several copies because I wanted my friends and colleagues to be aware of it and make of it what they will. If you would like to keep the tape please compensate me the $10 I paid for it. Dan Klein."
    - "Where There's Life" Discussing Sex, 06/28/1986; szasz_t_042; VHS (Box 77)
    - [untitled], szasz_t_041; VHS (Box 77)
    - [untitled], szasz_t_242; VHS; running time 160:00 (Box 89)
    - [untitled], szasz_t_243; VHS; running time 180:00 (Box 89)
- Subject files
  Szasz maintained his own research files on a wide range of topics. The listing below gives Szasz's original title, as it was written on the folder or on the material inside. For material without a title, one was assigned based on the material; these titles are given in square brackets [ ] to distinguish from Szasz's own. Types of material vary widely and include photocopies, reprints, clippings, retyped/edited news articles, handwritten notes, typed pages of quotations, programs/brochures, and more.
  - AAAIMH material [American Association for the Abolition of Involuntary Mental Hospitalization], includes membership forms, certificate of incorporation, form letters, platform statement, issues of newsletter (Box 116)
  - The Aged (Montreal, 11/84) (Box 116)
  - AIDS promotion, Madrid (Box 116)
  - Alexander, Franz (Box 116)
  - Alexander, George
  - Aliotta, A. (Box 116)
  - Allen, Francis A. (Box 116)
  - AM (Add's) (Box 116)
  - American leviathan 9/94 (Box 116)
  - Anderson, Sherwood (Box 116)
  - Arendt, Hannah (Box 116)
  - Arens, Richard (Box 116)
  - Arnold, Thurman (Box 116)
  - Auden, W.H. (Box 116)
  - [Austen Riggs Center] (Box 116)
  - A [misc.] (Box 116)
  - Babbitt, Irving (Box 116)
  - Bakan, David (Box 116)
  - Bateson, Gregory (Box 116)
  - Bauer, Peter T., 3 folders (Box 116)
  - Bazelon [David L.], Federal Appeals Court cases at which Bazelon presided; unfoldered, but found together and all labeled "Bazelon" in Szasz's hand; 4 folders (Box 117)
  - Bazelon, Judge David L., 2 folders (Box 117)
  - BB, abbreviation unknown; content appears to relate to frauds and charlatans (Box 117)
  - Beauvoir, Simone de (Box 117)
  - Beaver, James (Box 117)
  - Beaver, James E., 2 folders (Box 117)
  - Beecher, Henry K. (Box 118)
  - Beers, Clifford W. (Box 118)
  - Belli, Melvin (Box 118)
  - Benda, Julien (Box 118)
  - [Benedek, Istvan] (Box 118)
  - Bennett, Abram (Box 118)
  - [Betjeman, John], photocopied program from Centenary Gala (Box 118)
  - Bettelheim, Bruno (Box 118)
  - Bierce, Ambrose (Box 118)
  - [Biko, Steve] (Box 118)
  - Binger, Carl, related to Benjamin Rush (Box 118)
  - Binswanger, L. (Box 118)
  - Biomedical project 1975, research report on ethical, legal, and social implications of advances in biomedical research; primary investigator Peter G. Goldschmidt (Box 118)
  - Birnbaum, Morton (Box 118)
  - Blackwell, Elizabeth (Box 118)
  - Blaine, Graham B. (Box 118)
  - Blatt, Burton (Box 118)
  - Bleuler, Manfred (Box 118)
  - Bockoven, J. Sanbourne (Box 118)
  - Bogdan, Robert (Box 118)
  - Bohannan, Paul (Box 118)
  - Bohr, Niels (Box 118)
  - Book ads for duplicating, includes ad layouts, book jacket proofs, promotional brochures, fliers, etc.; 2 folders (Box 118)
  - Booker, Christopher (Box 118)
  - Boorstin, Daniel (Box 118)
  - Borchard, Edwin M. (Box 119)
  - Born, Max (Box 119)
  - Boverman, Maxwell (Box 119)
  - Braceland, F.J. (Box 119)
  - [Braibanti, Aldo], Italian man accused of witchcraft in 1968 (Box 119)
  - Braiman, Alex (Box 119)
  - Brainwashing (Box 119)
  - Branch, C.H. Hardin (Box 119)
  - Branden, Nathaniel (Box 119)
  - Breton, Andre (Box 119)
  - [Brief history of mental therapy], printout from website of chronology compiled by Robert F. Meinsma (Box 119)
  - The British mental hospital under the National Health Service (Box 119)
  - [Brussels hearing on psychiatry and human rights, June 1996] (Box 119)
  - Burger, Warren E. (Box 119)
  - Burnham, James (Box 119)
  - Burt, Cyril (Box 119)
  - CA case, 1982, case of Darlin June Cromer (Box 119)
  - Calas, Nicolas (Box 119)
  - Camus etc., mostly Camus and Sartre; includes comparison with Orwell; 2 folders (Box 119)
  - Camus, Albert (Box 119)
  - Canon law (Box 119)
  - Carstairs, George M. (Box 119)
  - [Cartoons I] (Box 119)
  - [Cartoons II] (Box 119)
  - [Cartoons III] (Box 119)
  - [Cartoons IV], 2 folders (Box 120)
  - [Cartoons V], 2 folders (Box 120)
  - [Cartoons, with topical subdivisions] (Box 120)
  - Cartoons for [illegible] (Box 120)
  - Cendrars, Blaise (Box 120)
  - "The Censarean", drafts of paper or essay by Andras Varkonyi (Box 120)
  - Chambers, Whittaker (Box 120)
  - Charen, Mona, includes letter from Citizens Commission on Human Rights International (Box 120)
  - Chargoff, Erwin (Box 120)
  - Chesler, Dr. Phyllis (Box 120)
  - The Chicago mental health clinic, retyped and edited articles from Chicago Daily News (Box 120)
  - [Chicago Psychoanalytic Society', statement on privileged communications (Box 120)
  - [Child abuse, sexual], includes publications on use of anatomically correct dolls (Box 120)
  - Chisholm. G.B. (Box 120)
  - Choosing (Box 120)
  - [Circumcision], includes material from 2d and 3d International Symposium; 2 folders (Box 120)
  - [Circumcision] (Box 121)
  - Circumcision January 1994 (Box 121)
  - Citizens Commission on Human Rights (CCHR), several of their reports open with a Szasz quote (Box 121)
  - [Coate, Morag] (Box 121)
  - Cobbett, William, 2 folders (Box 121)
  - [Cobbett, William], unfoldered material, found together in box; 2 folders (Box 121)
    See also Rush v. Cobbett.
  - [Cobbett, William, "The American Rush-light"], photocopy of book; 3 folders (Box 121)
  - Cohn, Norman (Box 121)
  - Coles, Robert (Box 121)
  - Coll. Papers 4/1/82 U. of C. Press, includes drafts and outlines of material by Szasz (Box 121)
  - Comfort, Alex (Box 121)
  - Corwin, Edward S. (Box 121)
  - [Court cases], state and federal; relating to narcotics, prescription drugs, prohibition, heroin, gambling, more; 2 folders (Box 122)
  - Cox, Harvey (Box 122)
  - Crime and punishment, retyped and edited articles from Minneapolis Sunday Tribune (Box 122)
  - Cults, 2 folders (Box 122)
  - [Custance, John] (Box 122)
  - C [misc.] (Box 122)
  - [Daly, Robert W.] (Box 122)
  - Davidson, Henry A., MD (Box 122)
  - Davis, D.B. (Box 122)
  - [Davis, Kingsley] (Box 122)
  - Death (Box 122)
  - [Deinstitutionalization], report from NIMH, series D no. 4, by Leona Bachrach (Box 122)
  - Delgado, Jose M.R. (Box 122)
  - [Democracy as mental disease] (Box 122)
  - Der Spiegel, article, "Pills in psychiatry: the gentle murder" (Box 122)
  - [Der Spiegel / Margot Erne], letter to the editor, in response to an article on Gunter Weigands, asking why Szasz's work is ignored (Box 122)
  - Dershowitz, Alan M. (Box 122)
  - Deutsch, Albert (Box 123)
  - Diagnosis (Box 123)
    See also folders starting with "Dx" below.
  - Dicey, A.V. (Box 123)
  - Disease (Box 123)
  - Djilas, Milovan (Box 123)
  - Dostoyevsky, Fyodor (Box 123)
  - Douglas, William O. (Box 123)
  - Douglass, Frederick (Box 123)
  - Drug ads (Box 123)
  - [Drug use, abuse] (Box 123)
  - Drugs, Germany (Box 123)
  - Dubos, Rene (Box 123)
  - Dumont, Matthew P., M.D. (Box 123)
  - Dworkin, Andrea (Box 123)
  - Dworkin, Ronald (Box 123)
  - DX, 2 folders (Box 123)
  - Dx not disease 5/97 (Box 123)
  - Edelman, Murray (Box 123)
  - Edwards, Jonathan (Box 123)
  - Einstein, Albert (Box 123)
  - Eisenberg, Leon (Box 123)
  - Elkins, [Stanley?] (Box 123)
  - Emerson, Ralph Waldo (Box 123)
  - Engel, George (Box 123)
  - Engelhardt, H. Tristram (Box 123)
  - English, Joseph T. (Box 123)
  - Epig. - whole collection (Box 123)
  - Erb, Wilhelm (Box 123)
  - [Esterson, Aaron] (Box 123)
  - Ethics of psychoanalysis (Misc.) (Box 123)
  - [Evans, R.L.] (Box 124)
  - [Expert testimony], Law and Human Behavior special issue, focused on psychologists as expert witnesses (Box 124)
  - Eysenck, Hans (Box 124)
  - [Faith healing], Free Inquiry vol. 6 no. 2 (special issue), with annotations/marginalia by Szasz (Box 124)
  - Farnsworth, Dana L. (Box 124)
  - Faulkner, William (Box 124)
  - Fawcett, Fred (Box 124)
  - Feinstein, Howard M. (Box 124)
  - Field, Mark G. (Box 124)
  - [Film - The Committed], proposal for documentary (Box 124)
  - FitzGerald, F. Scott (Box 124)
  - Fleck, Stephen (Box 124)
  - Fletcher, J. (Box 124)
  - Flew, Antony (Box 124)
  - For Sirhan review/ Kaiser Q's, mostly about Sirhan Sirhan (Box 124)
  - Forced feeding (Box 124)
  - Fort, Joel (Box 124)
  - Fortas, Abe (Box 124)
  - [Foucault, Michel] (Box 124)
  - Foudraine, Jan (Box 124)
  - Frank, Leonard Roy (Box 124)
  - Frank, Philipp (Box 124)
  - Frank, Viktor E. (Box 124)
  - Freedman, Lawrence Z. MD (Box 124)
  - Freedom and folly, retyped articles from the Los Angeles Times, on Zoltan Latinovits (Box 124)
  - Freud (Box 124)
  - Friedman, Milton (Box 124)
  - Fromm, Erich (Box 125)
  - F [misc.] (Box 125)
  - Gainfort, John (Box 125)
  - Galbraith, John Kenneth (Box 125)
  - Galen (Box 125)
  - Gann, Lewis (Box 125)
  - Garfinkel, Harold, status degradation ceremonies (Box 125)
  - Gay, Peter (Box 125)
  - [Generic drugs] (Box 125)
  - [Genetic engineering / Davos conference] (Box 125)
  - German / [illegible] (Box 125)
  - Gilder, George (Box 125)
  - Gillespie, R.D. (Box 125)
  - Gillouin, Rene (Box 125)
  - Gilmore, Gary (Box 125)
  - Ginsberg, Leon H. (Box 125)
  - Ginsburg, Sol W. (Box 125)
  - Ginzberg, Eli (Box 125)
  - Glover, Edward (Box 125)
  - [Goldwater] (Box 125)
  - Gordon, Sol (Box 125)
  - [Government documents, miscellaneous], committee and subcommittee hearings (Box 125)
  - de Grazia, Edward (Box 125)
  - Greenblatt, Milton, MD (Box 125)
  - Greenhill, Maurice H. (Box 125)
  - Grenander, M.E., signed and inscribed items, notes, drafts, clippings, etc.; 4 folders (Box 125)
  - Grob, Gerald (Box 126)
  - Grodzins, Morton, internment of Japanese Americans (Box 126)
  - Gross, Martin (Box 126)
  - Guttmacher, Manfred S., includes article about Szasz, with letters to the editor in response (Box 126)
  - Guyon, Rene (Box 126)
  - Hakeem, Michael (Box 126)
  - Haley, Jay, includes review by Haley of Szasz's Law, Liberty and Psychiatry; 2 folders (Box 126)
  - Hall, G. Stanley (Box 126)
  - Halleck, Seymour (Box 126)
  - Halpern, Abraham (Box 126)
  - [Hamann, Johann Georg] (Box 126)
  - Hamburg, David A. (Box 126)
  - Hardin, Garrett, includes text of lecture, "Abortion and human dignity" (Box 126)
  - Harlow, Harry F., includes draft of address on social deprivation in monkeys, with Margaret K. Harlow (Box 126)
  - Harre, Ron (Box 126)
  - Harrison, Jane Ellen (Box 126)
  - Hayakawa, S.I., clippings about AAAIMH and Szasz (Box 126)
  - Hayek, F.A. (Box 126)
  - Hazlitt, Henry (Box 126)
  - Health care cost (Box 126)
  - [Health insurance], coverage for plastic surgery, gender reassignment, etc. (Box 126)
  - Hentoff, Nat (Box 127)
  - Hewart, Lord (Box 127)
  - Higgins, A.C., survey of prestige among Syracuse University faculty (Box 127)
  - History of psyc. (& law), 2 folders (Box 127)
  - History - psych/law (Box 127)
  - [Homosexuality] (Box 127)
  - Horace (Box 127)
  - Horowitz, Irving L. (Box 127)
  - [Horwitz, Julius / Natural Enemies] (Box 127)
  - Hospital and Community Psychiatry Sept 1970, "The medical model in psychiatry" (Box 127)
  - Huizinga, J. (Box 127)
  - Humor / jokes (Box 127)
  - Hutchins, Robert M. (Box 127)
  - Hutschnecker, A. (Box 127)
  - Huxley, Aldous (Box 127)
  - H [misc.] (Box 127)
  - Illich, Ivan (Box 127)
  - Incompetence (Box 127)
  - [The Inner Room by Vera Randal] (Box 127)
  - Inquiry, 1979, clippings on a wide variety of topics (school shootings, homosexuality, incest, etc.), all dating from 1979; 2 folders (Box 127)
  - Insanity defense (Box 127)
  - Involuntary mental hospitalization (Box 128)
  - [Die Irrenfrage], material in German on "The madness question" (Box 128)
  - Israel paper, includes clipping on Brazilian cult (Box 128)
  - Jaffe, Jerome H. (Box 128)
  - James, William, paper by Jeffrey Rubin (Box 128)
  - [Janet, Pierre] (Box 128)
  - Jaspers, Karl (Box 128)
  - Jones, Ernest (Box 128)
  - Joyce, James (Box 128)
  - [The Judas gospel] (Box 128)
  - Jung (Box 128)
  - J [misc.] (Box 128)
  - Kant (Box 128)
  - Karinthy, Frigyes (Box 128)
  - Keller, Hans (Box 128)
  - Kendell, Ian (Box 128)
  - Kennedy, Ian, includes transcript of BBC talk on the English Mental Health Act; clippings of his Reith Lectures on "unmasking medicine" (Box 128)
  - Kennedy, Robert (Box 128)
  - [Kesey, Ken] (Box 128)
  - Kevorkian, NYT 6/28/95 (Box 128)
  - [King, Larry] (Box 128)
  - Kittrie, Nicholas [empty] (Box 128)
  - Knopfelmacher, Frank (Box 128)
  - Konrad, George (Box 128)
  - Kosinsky, Jerzy (Box 128)
  - Kraus, Karl, 2 folders (Box 128)
  - Kristol, Irving (Box 128)
  - Kubie, Lawrence S. (Box 128)
  - Kurtz, Paul (Box 129)
  - [La Gaccia, Helena] (Box 129)
  - Lacan, Jacques (Box 129)
  - Ladimer, Irving (Box 129)
  - [Lambo, Thomas A.], interview (Box 129)
  - Langer, Suzanne K. (Box 129)
  - Lasch, Christopher (Box 129)
  - Lasswell, Harold D. (Box 129)
  - [Law & psychiatry in Italy] (Box 129)
  - Lawrence, D.H. (Box 129)
  - Lea, Henry Charles (Box 129)
  - Lecky, William E.H. (Box 129)
  - Lehrman, Nathaniel (Box 129)
  - Leifer, Ronald, includes paper on Szasz ("The moral conflict of psychiatry"), letter acknowledging Leifer's nomination of Szasz for the Isaac Ray Award (Box 129)
  - Leighton, Alexander H. (Box 129)
  - Lemert, Edwin M. (Box 129)
  - Leonard, Frank (Box 129)
  - Leschnitzer, Adolf (Box 129)
  - Lesse, Stanley, item signed and inscribed to Szasz (Box 129)
  - Lewis, C.S. (Box 129)
  - Lewis, Thomas (Box 129)
  - Library / problem patron (Box 129)
  - Liebling, A.J. (Box 129)
  - Lifton, Robert J. (Box 129)
  - Lipton, Samuel D., reprint of paper on childhood tonsillectomy, signed and inscribed to Szasz (Box 129)
  - The Listener, clippings, some of which mention Szasz; draft of a piece by Szasz (Box 129)
  - [Lobotomies] (Box 129)
  - London / Richmond Ref's (Box 129)
  - London, Jack (Box 129)
  - [London, Jack] (Box 129)
  - London, Perry (Box 129)
  - [Lorand, Sander], history of the Psychoanalytic Institute at SUNY Downstate (Box 129)
  - Loria, Donald (Box 129)
  - The Lost Men of Massachusetts, retyped and edited articles from Boston newspapers on Bridgewater Mental Hospital (Box 129)
  - Louisell, David W. (Box 129)
  - Lowinger, Paul (Box 129)
  - MacAlpine, Ida (Box 130)
  - Mahonski, 3/20/84 (Box 130)
  - Maine, Harold, photocopied pages from his "If a man be mad" (1947); typescript of Szasz's edited version with his comments (Box 130)
  - Maistre, Joseph de (Box 130)
  - Malinowski, Bronislaw (Box 130)
  - Mandeville, Bernard (Box 130)
  - A Manual on psychiatry for dissidents, Bukovsky and Gluzman, inscribed "T, a gold mine for you!" on front; heavily annotated by Szasz (Box 130)
  - Marcuse, Herbert (Box 130)
  - Margolis, Joseph (Box 130)
  - Mark, Vernon H. (Box 130)
  - Marks, John, CIA, mind control (Box 376)
  - Marmor, Judd (Box 130)
  - Masserman, Jules H. (Box 130)
  - McCabe, Charles (Box 130)
  - McConnell, James V. (Box 130)
  - McGarry, A.L. (and Greenblatt) (Box 130)
  - Mead, George H. (Box 130)
  - Mechanic, David (Box 130)
  - Medical ethics (Box 130)
  - Medical opinion and review contra Szasz, letters to the editor, papers, articles, etc. criticizing Szasz (Box 130)
  - Medical slavery, includes paper by Henry Wood (Box 130)
  - Medicalization of mind 9/23/93 (Box 130)
  - Medvedev, Zhores (Box 130)
  - Meerloo, Dr. Joost A.M. (Box 130)
  - Melendy, Mary R. (Box 130)
  - Menninger, Karl, 2 folders (Box 130)
  - [Mental hospitalization in France] (Box 131)
  - Mental Patients Liberation Project (Box 131)
  - Messengers of Love, testimony regarding electro-shock therapy (Box 131)
  - Messinger, L. (Box 131)
  - Metesky, George, includes correspondence with Metesky and his sister Mae; correspondence with Metesky's lawyers, Irving Engel and Gene Anne Condon; clippings; court filings; 6 folders (Box 131)
  - MI: new rhetoric, old problems (Box 131)
  - Michels, Robert (Box 131)
  - Miller, Milton H. (Box 131)
  - Minus One, excerpt from "Disaster Area" by J. G. Ballard; photocopied and retyped (Box 131)
  - Mitscherlich, Alexander (Box 131)
  - Moore, Thomas V. (Box 131)
  - Moore, W.L. (Box 131)
  - Morgenthau, Hans J. (Box 131)
  - Morris, Charles, includes reprint of article signed and inscribed to Szasz (Box 131)
  - Morris, Robert (Box 131)
  - Mosher, Loren M., M.D. (Box 131)
  - Mount Sinai Hospital 6/4/72 (Box 131)
  - Mowrer, O. Hobart (Box 131)
  - MPT (anthology) (GS) (Box 131)
  - [Mrs. R.W.] (Box 131)
  - Müller, F. Max (Box 131)
  - Musto, David (Box 131)
  - Myrdal, Jan (Box 131)
  - The Myth of the [illegible], appears to be about quacks and charlatans (Box 131)
  - [Myth of mental illness?], several items are annotated "MoM" or "MMI" (Box 132)
  - Naish, J.M. (Box 132)
  - [National Council on Crime and Delinquency] (Box 132)
  - Nelson, Banjamin (Box 132)
  - New Dx [illegible] (Box 132)
  - The New Society, full issue (Box 132)
  - Newgard case (Box 132)
  - Newland, Sam (Box 132)
  - Nock, Albert J. (Box 132)
  - Noll, John (Box 132)
  - Nozick, Robert (Box 132)
  - On not initiating force (Box 132)
  - [Orlansky, Harold], photocopied article "An American death camp" from Politics, Summer 1948; retyped and edited (Box 132)
  - Ortega y Gasset (Box 132)
  - Orwell, George (Box 132)
  - O [misc.] (Box 132)
  - Pain ref. (Box 132)
  - Parrinder, Geoffrey (Box 132)
  - Parsons, Talcott (Box 132)
  - The patient has no rights (Box 132)
  - Patient Self Determination Act (PSDA) 5/97 (Box 132)
  - [Peters, Margot Szasz] (Box 132)
  - Peters, R.S. (Box 132)
  - Piaget (Box 132)
  - Pike, Luke Owen (Box 132)
  - Pines, Maya (Box 132)
  - Plath, Sylvia, story, "Johnny Panic and the Bible of Dreams" (Box 132)
  - Pols, "…review and critical evaluation of the work of Thomas S. Szasz…" (Box 133)
  - Pope Pius XII, edict on psychotherapy and religion (Box 133)
  - Potter, Stephen (Box 133)
  - Pound, Roscoe (Box 133)
  - [Prescriptions] (Box 133)
  - Psych. Ideol. (Refs) (Box 133)
  - [Psychiatric ethics / Bloch and Chodoff] (Box 133)
  - Psychiatric prisoners (Box 133)
  - The Psychiatrist as accessory to murder, relating to Robert Torsney, NYPD (Box 133)
  - Psychotherapy and the market (Box 133)
  - Quotations, 2 folders (Box 133)
  - Quotations for hysteria, 2 folders (Box 133)
  - Quotations for INH (Box 133)
  - Quotations Law, Liberty and Psychiatry (Box 133)
  - Quotations Law, Liberty and Psychiatry (Misc.) (Box 133)
  - Quotations MM (Box 133)
  - [Quotations, misc] (Box 133)
  - Raico, Ralph, includes article on Szasz (Box 133)
  - Rand, Ayn (Box 134)
  - Rangell, Leo, M.D. (Box 134)
  - Rashkis, Harold A. (Box 134)
  - Redlich, Fritz (Box 134)
  - Ref. (Box 134)
  - Ref's (Box 134)
  - References, Lexicon (Box 134)
  - [References, unidentified], footnotes for unidentified document (Box 134)
  - Reichenbach, Hans (Box 134)
  - Reid, Thomas (Box 134)
  - Religion, 2 folders (Box 134)
  - Reviews etc. re TS, bibliographies of reviews of Szasz's work (Box 134)
  - Riesman, David (Box 134)
  - Right to trial (Misc.) (Box 134)
  - Roazen, Paul, reprint of article, signed and inscribed to Szasz (Box 134)
  - Robinson, Grace, Dr. (Box 134)
  - Robinson, Robert (Box 134)
  - Robitscher, Jonas B., 2 folders (Box 134)
  - Rogow, Arnold, includes piece criticizing Szasz (Box 134)
  - Romains, Jules (Box 134)
  - Rorschach, workshop (Box 134)
  - [Rosario, Victor] (Box 134)
  - Rosen, John N. MD (Box 134)
  - Rosen, John N. MD, 2 folders (Box 135)
  - [Rush v. Cobbett] (Box 135)
    See also subject files for Cobbett, William and Rush, Benjamin.
  - [Rush, Benjamin], unfoldered material, found together in box; 4 folders (Box 135)
    See also [Rush v. Cobbett].
  - Russell, Bertrand (Box 135)
  - Sacco-Vanzetti case (Box 135)
  - Sachar, Abram Leon (Box 135)
  - Sachs, Oliver (Box 135)
  - Sander, Fred M., includes article by Sander about Szasz, and Szasz's response to it (Box 135)